# **Peter Koenders**

# **UI/UX & Graphic** Designer



I'm a versatile UI/UX designer with 20+ years of all-rounder industry experience. I originally trained in traditional and computer graphic design and transitioned into web. I have worked with small and large organisations. I apply attention to detail in all aspects of my work flow; definition and planning, research, design, technical, management and review.

- Implementation of UI/UX design process
- Estimating & proposal review
- · Iterative wire-framing, prototypes & concept design
- · Style guides & pattern libraries
- HTML prototypes & templates
- · Graphic design
- · Planning & management of projects

I am curious, interested in web accessibility and working with integration teams across diversified technologies and projects.

With professionalism, integrity and care, I work in a collaborative manner to plan, design and deliver unique, well-crafted, web-accessible solutions that are quick, optimised and built with best practices in mind.



+64 2115 51085



https://pkoenders.netlify.com



www.linkedin.com/in/peter-koenders



Westend, Palmerston North, 4410, New Zealand

# **Experiences**

# **Contractor & Volunteer**

June 2019 - Present day

## Sustainable Solutions, Muscular Dystrophy Association & Lynn Pronk

I have taken on contract and volunteer work on range of projects as a design professional and front-end developer to keep myself occupied and offer my skills where they can useful. Amongst these is the Muscular Dystrophy Association who are looking at a exciting opportunity to re-design their website to include full web accessibility.

## **Design Lead - Contract** June 2018 - August 2018

# Vodafone, Auckland, New Zealand

In my role as a Design Lead working with the Content Team, I was accountable for a range of UI design tasks.

# Responsibilities

# Digital brand update

Enhance portions of the Vodafone NZ public website and execute a digital brand update.

Design

Re-design web pages, journeys, components. Ensured brand guidelines are adhered to. Deliverables included design files and components, presented for a range of screen sizing and collaborate with stakeholders.

**Templates** 

Created template designs and components to be consistent, work independently and together as a whole.

Style guides and pattern libraries

Designed, built and managed style guides and pattern libraries allowing design teams to use consistent components from a shared source.

# **Senior Digital Designer**

2004 - 2018

# Datacom Systems Limited, Auckland, New Zealand

In my role as a Senior Digital Designer in the Digital Experience Team, I grew and developed indispensable skills. I worked with multiple teams and environments. I was accountable for a range of UI/UX, graphic design tasks and had a hand in front-end development.

# Responsibilities

#### Estimating and proposal review

Defined what efforts would be required for delivery. Review project plans and proposals and made suggestions where value could be added.

Design

Designer for a range of projects, both restrictive and customer facing. Deliverables included design files managed and styled at a component level, templates and prototypes. Iterative wireframes to clarify screen requirements, elements/components and functionality. Explored flows, scenarios and created design options based on analysis. .

### Style guides and pattern libraries

Designed, built and managed style guides and pattern libraries allowing design teams to use consistent components from a shared source.

## **HTML** prototypes

Created semantic and accessible HTML/SCSS prototypes and templates.

# Senior Digital Designer

2004 - 2018

## **Datacom Systems Limited (continued)**

#### **Projects**

### · Customer facing websites

At Datacom, I initially worked for Air New Zealand managing their CMS; designing and building homepage and landing page takeovers, updating content, integrating new designs and layouts. Other websites, which have since been updated; Bayleys, NZ Lotteries, Ballance, Spark and Fisher & Paykel Finance. Current websites include the HTML/CSS deliverables and translation to responsive design for Auckland Airports and UI/UX design and HTML/CSS deliverables for Aon Insurance.

#### · Micro-sites and module add-ons

Analysis, flow, wire-frame and design work for Chorus, Spark and Auckland Airports.

#### Web applications

UI/UX design and HTML deliverables for internal Cloud Services and Payroll applications. External application for Australian Red Cross Blood Service for their Organ Management System used by scientists and medical professionals.

#### · Customer portals

UI design and HTML deliverables for Kotahi Logistics. A customer portal for container ordering, tracking and management.

#### Intranets

UI design and HTML deliverables for internal intranet for Datacom. UI Design for Bupa Health. Integration with Microsoft CRM and Salesforce.

#### · Graphic design

Create and manage print material for internal projects, prepared and composed collateral for internal and external research, analysis and sales presentations.

#### · Internal innovation hackfests

I participated in annual internal innovation hackfests. Made myself available as a design resource and mentorship of graduates.

#### **Achievements**

- I worked across UX and front-end development with UI at my core.
- I introduced HTML style guides to assist integration teams implementing consistent components.
- Delivery of accessible and functional HTML templates and prototypes for integration teams and working across time zones.
- · I was two times winner for UI design at annual internal hackfest.

## **Web and Print Designer**

2001 - 2003

# **London Centre of Contemporary Music, London, United Kingdom**

The LCCM and the London College of Creative Media employed me to design their website. I also worked with their integration team to build their Student Management System. Other tasks I took on; design their identity logo, produce various print materials, course brochures, posters and stationery.

## **Designer**

1996 - 2001

## Contract UI Designer, London, United Kingdom

I worked for various design agencies across London in a variety of roles including; UI design for interactive TV, designer hand for Air New Zealand livery and British Telecom, where I was employed to design the UI for a child safe web browser.

### Designer

1993 - 1996

# Designer, Megabyte/Terabyte, Auckland

Multimedia designer on a range of interactive projects.

# Education

# Diploma of Computer Graphic Design

1992 - 1994

## Whanganui School of Design, Whanganui, New Zealand

Three year Diploma of Computer Graphic Design.

Delivery of an interactive design and typography project for final year.

# **Interests**

Outside of my professional interests, caring for my children keeps me busy as a sole parent. I also muck in garden, make chili jam, play the guitar and DIY stuff.

Cook more vegetarian food and grow more chilies.